## Meduna Oluwafemi

No 22, Adekanbi Taylor, Ogba Lagos. +2348104916575 femimeduna@gmail.com LinkedIn - linkedin Git - github

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry, Skilled in mobile first web application development. Fluent in English and excellent in communication and interpersonal skills. A fast learner with strong time management and multi-tasking skills. Strong work ethic in teams and individual settings to drive product success and process efficiency, strong problem solving skills and an analytical mindset.

## SKILLS

- Good working knowledge of project management concepts
- Good knowledge of HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Knowledge and experience querying noSQL and SQL databases(MySql, MongoDB)
- Knowledge and experience in multiple programming languages (Javascript, PHP, SASS)
- Knowledge and experience in multiple frameworks React.js, Yii2.
- Knowledge of Nodejs as a backend language.
- Ability to explain complex technical terms and systems to others.

# **PROJECTS**

- Building of a web platform for reporting online rights violations of individuals across Africa ripoti.africa
- Online Platform for learning edukoya
- Design and implementation of a future money value web application using React, SASS...
- Design and implementation of an expense tracker (executed using the MERN stack).

## EXPERIENCE

**NOVEMBER 2020 - PRESENT** 

The September Agency, Lagos - Software Engineer

- Liaise with network administrators, systems analysts, programmers, and other software engineers to resolve any defects in products or company systems
- Ensure that security and quality assurance best practices are followed throughout the entire software development life cycle
- Development of API Data bank for exam questions using Nodejs
- Implement backend workflow for UI components for MVP application using nocode tools.

- Design and Implementation of database architecture for MVP applications.
- Perform testing and shipping of code while identifying opportunities to optimize and fine-tune web applications thereby reducing functional errors in production as a result.

#### MAY 2020 - OCTOBER 2020

## Cotta and Cush Limited, Lagos - Software Engineer

- Translating user stories into designs and creating low fidelity designs from user stories to meet customer defined specifications.
- Design, development and testing of UI for business purposes using Yii2, Javascript,
  PHP, JQuery, SASS, Node.js etc and creating a mobile first responsive web application.
- Perform code review and identify functional gaps in web applications, and develop suitable solutions for said gaps.
- Perform testing and shipping of code while identifying opportunities to optimize and fine-tune web applications thereby reducing functional errors in production as a result.
- Translate customer design specifications into component-based technical designs, and estimate the level of effort to implement designs.
- Design and implementation of database architecture for web applications.

#### OCTOBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

## **Dufuna Code Camp, Lagos** - Software Engineering Trainee

- Used balsamiq to create mockups.
- Created the front end design and implementation of an e-commerce website using Html, CSS and Javascript
- Performed code reviews and identified bugs and functional gaps. Suggested solutions to resolve identified issues.

#### JANUARY 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

# **Ewekoro Works Staff Cooperative Multipurpose Society Limited, Ogun.**– *Intern Engineer(NYSC).*

- Conducted daily inventory and created a checklist to monitor maintenance tools, resulting in an improvement in tool tracking and by extension overall work rate.
- Collaborated with the IT department to install displays in strategic stations around the factory thereby enhancing the dissemination of information amongst employees.

- Organized training sessions geared towards work optimization between departments, increasing productivity by 30%.

JUNE 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2017

## Consolidated Engineering Services, Oyo. - Engineering Intern

- Optimized the storage arrangement which led to approximately 30% increase in available space.
- Worked on the installation and maintenance of a fire hydrant system, as a safety measure in preventing fire outbreaks in the plant's warehouses.
- Worked under the supervision of the safety manager to ensure a safe environment while adhering to all engineering safety rules, thereby limiting the risk of accidents onsite.

## TECHNICAL TOOLS

- Source Control(Git, Github).
- UI/UX (Balsamiq, Figma, Mobile first responsive).
- HTML, CSS, SASS
- Languages(Javascript, PHP).
- Frameworks(React.js, Yii2).
- Rest API (Nodejs)
- Database(MongoDB, Mysql).
- Management Software (Jira, Notion).

## CERTIFICATES

- Introduction to HTML(Coursera) University of Michigan
- Introduction to CSS(<u>Coursera</u>)University of Michigan

## LANGUAGES

- English Native or Bilingual Proficiency
- Yoruba Working Proficiency

## **EDUCATION**

Afe-Babalola University, Ado-Ekiti - B.Sc Mechatronics Engineering

AUGUST 2011 - OCTOBER - 2018

PROJECT: Design and Implementation of a smart irrigation system.

St. Catherine's College, Oyo - West African School Certificate

## **SEPTEMBER 2005 - JULY 2011**

# **ORGANIZATIONS**

- Open Source Community Africa (OSCA).
- NUESA (Nigerian University, Engineering Students Association)
- Love Made Foundation.